本片基于真实勇者事迹改编
在我父亲临死前 他说衰老最大的坏处
Before my father died, he said the worst thing about growing old
就是他人不再视你为“强者”
was that other men stopped seeing you as dangerous.
我一直记得 成为“强者”是何等的神圣 何等的荣耀
I've always remembered that, how being dangerous was sacred, a badge of honor
你要靠准则和信念活着
You live your life by a code, an ethos.
人人如此 它是能引领你回家的“海岸线”
Every man does. It's your shoreline. It's what guides you home.
相信我 你总是会想回家的
And, trust me, you're always trying to get home.
海豹第七分队 高跳低开跳伞训练 - 圣地亚哥 加州
圣地亚哥
菲律宾
当局称圈内交易集中在了哥斯达黎加
Authorities say the ring is centered in Costa Rica,
因为主要出口产品逐渐...
with the primary export being...
...尚不清楚毒品交易火拼是否与他们有关...
...widely unknown if the war on drugs is connecting them...
...在此地区...报复其使用...
...in the region have been known to retaliate using a...
...25000名士兵...
...25,000 troops...
...从美国起飞前往控制...
...flying from the US to control that...
我们能买个冰激凌吗?
Can we get some ice cream?
- 不行 我们得走了 - 你总说不行
- No, we gotta go. - You always say no.
- 好吧 你去买吗? - 不 你去买
- Well, are you gonna buy? - No, you buy.
好吧 今天吃什么口味的?
OK, what are we getting today?
- 百香果 - 好的 百香果
- Passion fruit. - OK, passion fruit.
澳洲坚果口味怎样?
How about macadamia nut?
...声称对发生在马尼拉
WO...claimed responsibility for the attack
国际学校的爆炸事件负责
at the International School in Manila.
你父亲喜爱阅读
Your father was a reader
丘吉尔的书自然必读 还有福克纳和有关图康萨的著作
Churchill, of course, but also Faulkner and books about Tecumseh.
他喜欢将人物画得方方正正的艺术家
He loved artists who painted people with bodies that looked like boxes.
我对此不敢苟同
I 'd give him hell about that
他却说 “你得看见本质”
He'd just say, "You gotta look harden "
马格里斯大使一直是在该地区
Ambassador Margullies had long been a strong supporter
进行的联合反恐行动的强力支持者
of joint counterterrorism operations conducted within this region.
目前尚无组织声称对国际学校爆炸事件负责
Not one group has yet claimed responsibility for the attacks on the International School.
- 你的咖啡 洛克 - 谢谢 女士
- Here's your coffee, Rorke. - Thank you, ma'am.
（洛克上尉 铜星奖章获得者 中央司令部4役期）
- 听起来不错 谢谢你 - 你又迟到了 戴夫
- Sounds good, thank you. - You're late again, Dave.
（海军上士戴夫 年度最佳水兵
太平洋司令部5役期 中央司令部2役期）
你这是要干嘛?
What do you got going on over here?
《准爸爸》 - 准爸爸须知真相 窍门 建议
- 你开玩笑吧 伙计? - 我们谁都还没告诉呢
- Are you serious, man? - We're not telling anyone yet.
不过你看起来有点紧张 是不?
You a little nervous, though, huh?
上次去检查 孩子突然间就冒出来了
Last time I checked, they don't come with directions.
是啊 可不是么
Yeah, tell me about it.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
我哥们要做爸爸了
My man here is having a baby.
嘿 恭喜啊
Hey, congratulations.
嘿 大家听着 洛克要做爸爸了！
Hey, everybody, Rorke's having a baby.
恭喜 洛克！
WOCongratulations, Rorke!
喔！
Whoo!
- 我刚说啥了? - 别担心了 哥们
- What did I just say? - Ah, don't worry about it, man.
你会表现很棒的 我真替你高兴 你会成为好爸爸的
You're gonna be awesome. I'm so excited for you, man. You're gonna be a good dad.
嘿 明天杰姬和我要去海滩
Hey, tomorrow Jackie and I are heading down to the beach.
带桑迪和孩子们来吧 我给你多带块冲浪板去
Bring Sandy and the kids. I'll bring an extra board for you.
- 你知道我不会冲浪 - 我知道你不会 但是家人
- You know I don't surf. - I know you don't surf, but it'll be good
- 聚在一起多好啊 - 好吧
- to get the families together. - All right.
不过既然你通知了酒吧所有人 明天试着“控制”住自己
But now that you've told everyone in the bar, try and contain yourself tomorrow.
我会努力的
I will try.
哥斯达黎加
“看见本质” 你父亲所说的
"Look harden " your father would say.
我知道他并不只是指那些方方正正的抽象画
I always knew he wasn't just talking about those boxy abstract paintings.
世界在其伪装之下危机四伏
There 's threats everywhere, and the world is draped in camouflage.
这会疼吗?
不会 只是会有一点刺痛...
孩子们好吗?
克里斯多
啊?
Huh?
嘿 我马上下来 好吗?
Hey, I'll be right down, all right?
随你 老大
Whatever you say, Boss.
旅途如何?
WOHow was the ride?
今天上午我从哥伦比亚出发
I left Colombia this morning.
- 一天内从哥伦比亚到这儿? - 小意思
- Colombia to here in one day? - Piece of cake.
知道吗 克里斯多身家估计
Anyway, estimates say that Christo is worth
- 有近10亿美元了 - 10亿?
- close to a billion. - That's with a "B"?
是啊 他还回馈许多给这里的“社交圈”
Yeah, and he gives back a lot to this community over here
医疗诊所 学校 政治献金
with medical clinics, schools, political donations,
什么都有 所以情况是
you name it, so this is the deal:
他们在这儿都对他相当忠诚
They are extremely loyal to him over here.
药品管理局什么时候才把他交给我们?
When did the DEA hand him over to us?
等他们拦截到装载苏制武器的波音707吧
When they intercepted a 707 of his filled with Soviet weapons.
听着 中情局说国家安全局的人
Listen, Langley says that the boys over at NSA,
在东南亚发现一些有趣的情报
they found some interesting intercepts connecting Christo
克里斯多和一个伊斯兰圣战组织有关联
to a jihadist network out of Southeast Asia.
显然 克里斯多和其中一人控制组织
Apparently, Christo and one of the guys running the network,
他们是从小就相识
they're childhood friends.
你父亲的爷爷在二战时
Your father's grandfather gave up his life
驾驶B-24轰炸机牺牲了
flying a B-24 in World War ll.
他一直控制着“解放者”以使其他人安全跳伞
He kept the Liberator aloft just long enough for everyone to jump,
最后同飞机一起坠毁牺牲了
and then he went down with the plane.
这就是你血管里淌着的血
That's the blood that courses in your veins.
- 爸爸 我能跟你一起去吗? - 你要一起去?
- Daddy, can I come with you? - You want to come with me?
知道那里多冷吗?这样吧
Did you feel how cold it is out there? I'll tell you what,
去跟你妈妈一起照看小宝宝
go hang out with Mommy for a little while, help out with the baby.
等我回来如果你还想去 我就带你一起
When I come back in, if you still want to go out, I'll take you out with me.
- 约定了? - 约好了 快 走吧
- Promise? - I promise. Hurry up, go.
- 怎么样 长官? - 怎么了 兄弟?
- What's going on, sir? - What's up, brother?
没什么 伙计
Nothing much, man.
我知道你在纽约玩过
Now, I know you got the New York heritage,
不过这可不像躺在斯坦顿岛那样简单
but this isn't exactly like sitting back in Staten Island.
你得努力才能冲过浪花
You got to actually work hard to get through the surf.
- 是的 我知道 - 你都入队12多年了
- Yeah, I know. - Twelve-plus years on the Teams,
还不知道怎么冲浪?
and you don't know how to do this?
嘿 等你有5个孩子 哥们
Hey, wait till you have five kids, man.
你就知道有多少时间玩冲浪了
You'll see how much time you got to play in the surf.
你准备好喝海水了吗?
You ready to get in the drink or what?
好了 伙计 开路吧
All right, man, lead the way.
- 好吧 别搞砸了 - 好的
- All right, don't embarrass us. - All right.
你父亲是我的“老板” 而我是他的“大副”
Your father was my Boss, and I was his Chief
相互熟知让我们关系紧密
What we knew about each other strengthened our bond as operators.
我们情如兄弟
There was a brotherhood between us,
比家人之间还要相互依赖
and we depended on each other more than a family.
图康萨说 “兄弟同心”
Tecumseh said, "Although a single twig will break,
“其利断金”
a bundle of twigs is strong. "
你走过头了！我在二楼有铁门的房间
好的 好的 谢谢
OK, OK, gracias.
哇哦 真不敢相信
Wow, this is unbelievable.
我还是不敢相信你在这地方点中餐
I still can't believe you ordered Chinese in this place.
很好吃的
It's really good.
两个单词 18分
Double word score, 18 points.
- “白痴”? - 伤心了吧 甜心
- "Dumb"? - Read it and weep, sugar.
我不会伤心的
I'll try not to.
看看 看看 我得了38分
Look at this, look at this. Thirty-eight points for me.
“adumbrating”?这不是单词啊
"Adumbrating," that's not even a word.
好吧 首先 它读作“adumbrating”
OK, first of all, it's pronounced "adumbrating,"
而且意思是“假装 预示”
and it means pretending, foreshadowing.
嗯...
Hm...
猜猜今晚该谁买单 甜心?
Guess who's buying dinner tonight, sugar.
好吧
Fine.
世上总少不了这种耍小聪明搭档
In most cases, officers get tactical partners.
中情局给我派了个拼字作弊的
Langley sets me up with some son of SCRABBLE hustler.
是拼字大师好不好?别搞错了
WOSCRABBLE Yoda, OK? Get it right.
- 多少钱? - 免费的
- How much do I owe you? - Nada.
糟糕
Shit.
队里的兄弟们都曾出生入死
Our platoon was headed downrange.
怀明 我们的狙击手
We had Weimy, our sniper
他在莫哈韦沙漠中长大
He grew up in the middle of the Mojave Desert.
（一等士官怀明 勇士铜星奖章 紫心勋章 陆军嘉奖奖章获得者
南方司令部1役期 中央司令部2役期）
童年时最大的乐趣就是在杂货店
Most excitement he found as a kid was bowling frozen turkeys
把冰冻火鸡当保龄球来打
down the aisle at the grocery store.
雷是我们的通讯员
Ray, our comms guy, our radioman,
他成长于洛杉矶东部帮派地区
he grew up in East LA gangland.
（二等士官雷 银星勋章、勇士铜星奖章获得者
中央司令部2役期 太平洋司令部1役期）
因在行动中救出受伤队友而获银星勋章
He had a Silver Star for pulling a wounded teammate out of the fray.
桑尼硬地像块岩石
Sonny, he was made of granite.
（一等士官桑尼 7年拆弹手生涯
南方司令部2役期 中央和太平洋司令部各1役期）
这家伙都不愿做俯卧撑
This guy didn't even do push-ups
因为他担心胸肌会太大
'cause he was afraid his chest was gonna get too big.
艾杰30岁后才入队
Ajay joined the Teams late in his 30s.
（二等士官艾杰 中央司令部2役期 太平洋司令部1役期）
他早前曾是泰拳手
He'd been a Muay Thai fighter early in life.
更早前 他成长于特立尼达岛的贫穷家庭
Before that, he grew up dirt-poor in Trinidad.
麦奇入队20年了
Mikey had 20 years in the Teams.
（一等士官麦奇 太平洋司令部5役期 中央司令部1役期）
但是因为他的谦逊 你甚至都看不出来
But as humble as he was, you'd never even know it.
他头盔里放了张妻子的照片 口袋里则有她的一束头发
He kept a picture of his wife in his helmet and a lock of her hair in his pocket.
不多话的家伙
Quiet as the breeze.
最后是高级军士
And finally, Senior Chief
我真的不能说太多他的事...
I couldn't really tell you much about him...
也不愿被他“审讯”
than have to be interrogated by him.
在家最后一晚
That last night at home,
你会想着自己本可做个好父亲
you think about how you could have been a better dad,
好丈夫
a better husband.
想着你本该读的睡前故事或遗忘的周年纪念日
That bedtime story you should have read or that anniversary you forgot.
你不期望家人理解你所做的
You don't expect your family to understand what you're doing,
只期望他们能接受一切
you just hope they'll accept it.
当你回到家时 能重拾旧日温馨
When you get home, you hope you can pick up right where you left off
怎么了?
What up?
- 你神经放松了吗? - 是的 是的
- You putting the wild bunch down? - Yeah, yeah.
嘿 军士 介意我们说几分钟吗 伙计?
Hey, Senior, you mind giving us a couple minutes, man?
- 不 你随意 老大 - 谢了
- Nah, you got 'em, Jefe. - Thanks.
嘿 伙计们 你们知道我只在
Hey, fellas, you know I only got so many speeches
特殊时刻或行动前才要说两句的 不过 额...
in a given work-up or deployment, but, uh...
...不过正如小队成立时军士和我曾说的
...it's like Chief and I said right at the beginning of this platoon:
一旦我们出征 一旦直升机准备载我们前往作战区域
Once we step off on campaign, once this bird's ready and we're downrange,
后方一切都要安稳
everything back home needs to be in balance.
如果我们到了那儿却因后方误事
We 're not gonna be worth a damn to each other or ourselves
那就既对不起自己 也对不起队友了
if we get over there and something 's out of whack.
我是说 如果家庭有问题
I mean, if things aren't right with the family,
经济有问题或是其他什么事情
things aren't right with the finances or something's off;
都会让我们不安稳 所以出发前就得安顿好一切
it's gonna put us all out of balance, so we need to have that tight before we launch.
如果谁有问题 现在就提
If somebody's got an issue, bring it up.
军士能帮 我能帮 大家互相都能帮忙
Chief can take care of it, I can take care of it. Everybody's got each other's back.
要确保无任何杂念 这样行动前
Let's make sure we lock that down so when we 're ready to roll,
我们就能全身心投入任务
all our focus is on the mission.
敬所有曾参与战斗的勇士
For all those who have been downrange,
敬我们以及像我们这样的人 “少数拯救多数”
to us and those like us, damn few.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. - Hear, hear.
我还是喜欢詹姆士这个名字
I still like the name James.
我会考虑的 如果是男孩的话
I'll think about it, if it's a boy.
过来
Come here.
- 我为你自豪 - 谢谢 宝贝
- I'm proud of you. - Thanks, baby.
嘿 小子 让你妈妈离卡罗尔阿姨远点
Hey, little one, you make sure you keep Mama away from Aunt Carol.
我可不喜欢烟味
I don't like that chain-smoking at all.
我知道了 上尉
I got it, Lieutenant.
- 好吧 - 别担心
- OK. - It's gonna be OK.
- 好的 - 我会好好的
- All right. - It's gonna be fine.
尽量保持好这发型 好吗?
Try to Keep this as long as you can for a while, yeah?
还有别的吗 “长官”?
Anything else, Commander?
我希望第一个孩子出生时你能在场
Yeah. I'd like to be able to look into your eyes when our first child is born.
你知道我会尽力的
You know I'll do my best.
我爱你 宝贝
I love you, baby.
我也爱你
Love you.
战争是国家意志的体现
War is a country of will.
容不得半点同情心
There 's no room for sympathy.
如果不愿抛弃一切 你就已经输了
If you're not willing to give up everything, you've already lost.
我们抓到她了 不过她干掉了吉伯特
她在这里 老板
我做了什么?告诉我做错了什么！
我是个墨西哥医生 你想怎么样?
告诉我 你们美国人他妈的凭什么
Tell me, what is it about you Americans that makes
以为有权砸我“饭碗”
you feel entitled to fuck with the way I make my living?
乌克兰
我叫丽萨冯 是个来自墨西哥的医生
你想怎么样?我已经说了我什么都不知道
我知道你是谁 莫拉里斯小姐 我知道你给谁做事
I know who you are, Miss Morales, and I know who you work for.
所以何不节约大家时间
So why don't you save us both some time
告诉我你所知道的?
and tell me exactly what you think you know?
我照顾过跟你老妈一般的母亲 听懂了吗 混蛋?
感觉如何 莫拉里斯小姐?
How did that feel, Miss Morales?
望您能对“服务”满意
Have a great day at the spa.
关掉手机免提
别把她弄死了 等她开口了打给我
好的 老板
Si, jefe.
说不说?
比两只闷死在羊毛袜的老鼠感觉还热吧?
It's hotter than two rats screwing in a wool sock out there, yeah?
跟非洲一样...人猿泰山都受不了
Africa-hot... Tarzan couldn't take this heat.
不管怎样 事情是这样的 你们该上场了
Anyway, here's the deal. Time to get your frogman on.
熄灯 三天前
Lights. Three days ago,
两名中情局特工 沃尔特·罗斯和丽萨·莫拉里斯
two CIA agents, a Walter Ross and a Miss Lisa Morales,
在哥斯达黎加的旅馆住所内遭遇
were ambushed inside their hotel room here in Costa Rica
不明武装分子袭击
by a unknown amount of heavily armed assholes.
不幸的是罗斯被杀而莫拉里斯被抓了
Unfortunately, Mr. Ross was murdered, and Miss Morales has been abducted.
我们相信这是一个叫
We believe that this has been the work
米哈伊尔·特意科维奇的人干的 又名克里斯多
of a guy named Mikhail Troykavitch, aka Christo.
上尉会给你们他的资料
LT's going to give you the skinny on him.
谢谢 军士 米哈伊尔·特意科维奇 又名克里斯多
Thanks, Senior. Mikhail Troykavitch, aka Christo.
情报显示这家伙自90年代后期起就一直在
This guy is believed to have been working cocaine-for-weapons deals
俄罗斯黑手党 哥伦比亚游击队和墨西哥毒贩之间
between the Russian mafia, the FARC guerrillas, and the Mexican drug cartels
做可卡因换武器的生意
ever since the late 1990s.
在她被抓前 莫拉里斯正在寻找克里斯多
Now, before she was captured, Morales was working a possible link
和这个家伙——阿布·谢布尔之间的联系
between our boy Christo and this guy Abu Shabal.
万物之主阿拉万岁
Glory to Allah, Lord of the worlds,
他创造了我们穆斯林
who has created us as Muslims
引领我们进行圣战
and delivered us with the jihad on his direct path.
遵循真主旨意直至审判日者才能得到和平
Peace be upon those who follow his direct path till the Day of Judgment.
我要告诉你们美国人
Let me explain this to you Americans.
我们不是分裂分子
We are not separatists.
我们车臣不属于任何国家
We Chechens are not a legal part of anyone,
但是你们美国人通过强制推行政策
but you Americans are willingly or unwillingly assisting
和侵占所有穆斯林国家
in the genocide of our people by demanding that we obey certain rules,
一直在有意或无意地帮助屠杀我们族人
and by your continued occupation of all Muslim countries.
以万能 神圣的真主之名起誓
With the grace of Allah, glorious and exalted is he,
我们没有安全保障 那美国也不得安宁
America will never be safe until safety becomes a reality for us.
真主万岁
Allahu Akbar
阿布·谢布尔是车臣恐怖分子
Abu Shabal is a Chechen terrorist
他和别斯兰学校人质事件有关
who's associated with the Beslan School Massacre.
他一直活跃于印度尼西亚和菲律宾的训练基地
He's been jumping between training camps in Indonesia and the Philippines.
目前克里斯多和他之间的联系目前还有点不清楚
Now, the connection between Christo and Abu Shabal is still a little bit fuzzy,
不过如果这是莫拉里斯正在查的线索
but if this was the lead that Morales was working on,
那就很可能是她被绑架的原因 军士?
it could be why she was abducted. Senior?
好的 这是莫拉里斯的个人资料
All right, this is a personnel recovery of Miss Morales.
好的 有问题吗?
All right, who's got questions?
军士 你有最新数据吗
Senior Chief, you got any updated source intel
关于敌营人数的 还有巡逻队呢?
on numbers inside the camp, and what about roving patrols?
大约8-10个 伙计 但我们对巡逻队一无所知
Maybe eight to ten, bro, but we don't know anything about roving patrols.
你只能假设他们在那儿
You're just gonna have to assume that they're out there
布防严密 还是专业人士
walking around, squared away. They do this for a living, too.
军士 敌方武器装备如何?
Senior, what kind of weapons-on-target are we looking at?
重武器 这些家伙是毒贩子
Heavy weapons. These guys are narco-traffickers,
所以他们什么都会有 从苏制DShK大口径机枪
so they can have anything from Soviet-bloc DShKs.
到美制M2HP12.7毫米重机枪都有可能
They could have M2HP, .50-cals out there, we don't know.
所以如果可以的话 我建议你们带火箭筒
So if there is a weapons' emplacement up there, I suggest you guys bring rockets.
当然火箭筒威力大 这样就有取胜把握了
Of course, rockets and foliage don't match, so make sure you got a clear shot.
好的 还有什么?
All right, what else?
她自己能走得动吗?
Any idea whether she's ambulatory or not?
现场都是血迹
There was a ton of blood on the scene,
我们肯定大部分是罗斯的
and a lot of it was Mr. Ross', we confirmed that.
莫拉里斯的可能也有 不过这些人都是禽兽
Miss Morales may have bled there, too, but these guys are savages,
所以只能假设她根本走不动了
so you're gonna have to assume that she is non-ambulatory,
必须带工具把她抬出来
so you're gonna have to bring stuff to carry her out.
2分钟后跳伞
Two minutes to drop.
嘿 上尉
Hey, LT.
你一定要告诉我们那人是谁 等回来好去揍他一顿
You got to let us know who that guy is, so when we get back, we can kick his ass.
你说谁呢?
What guy?
给你做这鸟发型的家伙
The guy that gave you that fucked-up haircut.
- 操 - 该死 桑尼
- Fuck. - Damn, Sonny,
还好意思说 你自己不也是“大光头”先生
you should be the last guy to talk. You look like the Dominican Mr. Clean.
我的头跟你的金牙一样亮 是吧?
That means my head shines like your gold teeth, huh?
别这样说
Don't be like that,
- 很伤自尊的 - 开舱门！
- that's harsh. - Ramp!
戴上面罩
Mask up.
伙计 告诉你 现在唯一比这要好的事就是做爸爸了
Man, I tell you what. The only thing better than this right here is being a dad,
换尿布除外 不过...
except for that whole changing diaper thing, but...
不管怎样桑迪会干的 所以...
...Sandy does that for me anyway, so...
其实我还是挺期待的
I'm actually looking forward to it.
黑胡 10秒准备
Blackbeard, green light in ten.
5秒
Five.
黑胡呼叫基地 黑胡呼叫基地 我是黑胡
Blackbeard Main, Blackbeard Main, this is Blackbeard Actual.
无线电测试 请回
Radio check. Over.
黑胡呼叫基地 黑胡呼叫基地 我是黑胡 请回
Blackbeard Main, Blackbeard Main, this is Blackbeard Actual. Over.
收到 我是基地
Roger; Actual This is Main,
- 清楚收到 - 收到 基地
- We have you Lima Charlie. - Roger, Main.
所有人员已落地 已通过“雷鸟”区
All boots are on the ground. I pass T-bird.
目前有什么动静吗?
Any traffic for my station at this time?
黑胡 侦查显示第二地点车辆
Actual, imagery picked up an increase in traffic
有所增多 应该是敌人快反部队
at secondary location, known to be enemy QRF,
距主地点8公里
eight clicks from primary target.
河流特种部队特战艇会在6点钟时接应你们撤退
The SWCC boats will insert at 0600 for your extract.
- 收到吗? - 收到 基地
- How copy? - Roger, Main.
- 准备好了吗? - 好了 长官
- You ready? - Roger that, sir.
距目标大约4.7公里 方位355
We got about 4.7 clicks at three-five-five.
出发
Take it out.
皮鞭 一分钟准备
Whiplash, one minute out.
30秒准备
Thirty seconds.
10秒
Ten by ten.
皮鞭 行动
Whiplash, go.
所有人员已上船
All boots on deck.
绳索已解开
Line secure.
皮鞭 水桶1号和2号已出发
Whiplash, Bucket One and Two are out.
皮鞭 我是黑胡 无线电测试 请回
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard. Radio check. Over.
黑胡 我是皮鞭 清楚收到
Blackbeard, it's Whiplash. Have you loud and clear.
请原地待命
Standing by on the set.
收到 皮鞭 你到我这里还有多久?
Roger, Whiplash. What is your ETA to my pos?
预计20分钟
ETA 20 mikes.
注意 “大乌鸦”已放飞 接近中
Be advised, Raven is in flight and pushing to your location.
不！
No!
嘿 长官 我们得行动了
Hey, sir, we gotta go.
明白 出发
Roger. Take it out.
敌众我寡 我想让你跟我们一起去
I feel like we're pretty thin. I'd like to take you guys with us.
上士 特战舟艇分队正在赶来 “大乌鸦”也在朝我飞来
Chief, I got a SBT coming up on-step. I got a Raven pushing my pos.
怀明和我处于绝佳掩护位置
Weimy and I are in good overwatch position,
我得不间断向基地汇报
and I got to keep reporting back to Blackbeard Main.
- 我们要呆在这儿 - 明白
- We're staying here. - Roger that.
- 看紧了 - 收到
- Keep it tight. - Got it.
皮鞭 我是黑胡 突击队要提前行动了
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard. Assault force is moving to the target early.
请火速支援
Request immediate fire support.
黑胡 我是皮鞭 收到
Blackbeard, it's Whiplash. Good copy.
接受请求 15分钟内到达你处
Requesting fire support. Pushing to your location in 15 mikes.
皮鞭 我是黑胡 已接控“大乌鸦”
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard. I have positive control of the Raven.
上士 你就位了吗?
Chief, are you set?
上士 上士 停下
Chief; Chief; hold it
1点钟方向 岗哨底下
One o'clock, base of the tower.
明白
Got him.
门前安全
You're clear to the door
后门出现两名敌人
I've got two squilters coming out the back door.
突进！
Going in!
- 安全！ - 全部安全！
- Clear! - All clear!
怀明  11点钟方向 卡车驾驶座上
Weimy, eleven o'clock. Driver's side, truck.
明白
Got him.
操
Fuck.
- 来啊 - 突进！突进！
- Come on. - Go in! Go in!
- 安全！ - 全部安全！
- Clear! - All clear!
- 目标安全 - 上士 我去帮麦奇
- Target's secure. - Chief, I'm going to get Mikey.
上尉 我是上士 目标安全
LT, this is Chief. Target is secure.
请确认目标
Stand by for confirmation of the package.
注意 麦奇受伤 麦奇受伤 确认状况中
Be advised Mikey is down. Mikey is down. Status to follow.
收到 目标确认
Roger. You have the package.
上士 我找到个手机
Chief, I got his cell phone.
上尉?上尉?
LT? LT?
上士 北边来了两辆敌军车辆
Chief, looks like you have two aggressor vehicles approaching from the north,
约一分钟内到达 你可乘西门外卡车离开
about one mike out. You can take the truck outside the west door
我们在撤退点会合
Meet us at extract.
莫拉里斯小姐 我要带你回家了
Miss Morales, I'm bringing you home.
我只需要问你点问题
I just need to ask you a few questions.
你母亲姓什么?
What's your mother's maiden name?
罗萨丽斯
Rosales.
你在哪条街出生?
What street you were born on?
温泉街
Hot Springs.
好的 坚持住
All right. Just hang on.
皮鞭 北边有敌军快反部队赶来
Whiplash, we have enemy QRF approaching from the north.
收到 北边有敌军快反部队赶来
Roger. You have enemy QRF coming in from the north.
上士 你得马上离开
Chief, you need to start your exfil now.
- 我们在第二撤退点会合 - 收到
- We 'll meet you at secondary extract. - Roger that.
嘿 兄弟们 我们要走了！
Hey, boys, we gotta roll!
糟了 长官 是敌车辆
Shit. Sir, it's those trucks,
- 大约1000码 - 是的
- about 1,000 yards. - Yep.
女士 我马上带你走
Ma'am, I'm taking you out right now.
嘿 上士 他眼睛中枪 耳朵后面开了个口子
Hey, Chief, he took a round to the eye with the exit wound behind the ear.
他还活着 但是我们得立刻离开！
He's alive, but we gotta get moving now!
怀明 我们出来了
Weimy, coming out.
我们在集合点汇合
We'll meet you at the rally point.
我们走！我们走！开车！
Let's go! Let's go! Move it!
- 小心！左边有敌人！ - 右转！右转！
- Heads up! Fast movement on the left! - Right turn! Right turn!
嘿 伙计 我们到不了第二撤退点了
Hey, man, we're not going to make it to secondary extract.
我得找条路出来 注意看路
I got to find us a route. Stay on this road.
- 左边 左边 左边 - 左转！左转！
- Left, left, left. - Left turn! Left turn!
麦奇 挺住 兄弟！
Mikey, come on, buddy.
嘿 上士！
Hey, Chief!
我们到不了第二撤退点了
We're not gonna make secondary extract!
- 无论如何都要赶到 伙计！ - 抓紧！
- You're gonna have to figure it out, man! - Hold on!
加油 挺住 挺住
Come on. Stay with me. Stay with me.
挺住
Stay with us.
加油 麦奇 醒醒 醒醒 加油 伙计
Come on, Mike. Wake up. Wake up. Come on, man.
- 接敌！ - 加速 加速
- Contact! - Pick it up, pick it up.
上士！我们可以赶到集合点！
Yo, Chief! We can make it to rally point!
- 很好！告诉上尉！ - 加油 伙计
- Sounds good! Pass it to LT! - Come on, man.
呼叫上尉 呼叫上尉 我是突击队 我们刚错过第二撤退点
LT, LT, this is assault team. We just lost the secondary extract.
重复一遍 我们刚错过第二撤退点
I say again, we just lost secondary extract.
前往集结点中 收到吗 请回?
Moving to rally point. How copy, over?
- 大约还有1公里 - 麦奇 醒醒
- We're about a click out. - Mikey, wake up.
还有一公里！
One click out!
起来 麦奇 醒醒 加油 兄弟
Let's go, Mike. Wake up. Come on, buddy.
加油 麦奇！醒醒！
Come on, Mikey! Wake up!
- 好了吗? - 可以发射
- Good? - Backstage clear.
发射！
Rocket out!
他没呼吸了！
He's not breathing!
- 呼吸 麦奇！ - 我们上来了！我们上来了！
- Breathe, Mikey! - We're up! We're up!
上士 把你的M4卡宾枪给我！
Chief, let me get your M-4!
长官 撤退船只在哪里?
Sir, what's the status on those boats?
撤退时跟皮鞭失去联系了
I lost Whiplash on the run.
跟他们说过行动提前了 皮鞭正在火速赶来
Told 'em you hit the target early. They're coming in hot.
- 收到 - 操！撑住 伙计
- Roger that. - Fuck! Take this, man.
呼吸 麦奇 加油 麦奇
Breathe, Mikey. Come on, Mikey.
- 他没脉搏了 - 后方接敌！
- I got no pulse. - Contact rear!
后方接敌！
Contact rear!
我靠！
Holy shit!
子弹飞进...
Taking rounds in...
加速 加速
Pick it up. Pick it up.
艾杰！快反部队在后面！
Ajay! QRF coming up the rear!
皮鞭！皮鞭！第二撤退点废了
Whiplash! Whiplash! Secondary extract is burnt.
正赶往第三撤退点
Moving to tertiary extract.
一共8人 7名队员 一名目标
I have eight packs, seven Sierras, one package.
目标多处受伤
Package with multiple wounds.
一名队员头部中枪
The Sierra has gunshot wound to the head.
撤退会很艰难
This will be a hot extract.
什么情况?！
What the fuck?!
- 哦 该死！ - 麦奇 趴下！
- Oh, shit! - Mikey, stay down!
- 按倒他 伙计！ - 我他妈在哪儿?
- Keep him down, man! - Where the fuck am I?!
- 冷静 兄弟 - 麦奇醒了 麦奇醒了
- Calm down, brother. - Mikey's up, man. Mikey's up.
趴下 兄弟 冷静 放松 我们马上就突围出去了
Stay down, brother. Calm. Be easy. We're almost out of here.
我们马上就突围出去了
We're almost out of here.
麦奇！
Mikey!
- 坚持住 兄弟 - 我们在哪儿?
- Hang on, buddy. - Where are we?
- 在撤退路上 - 怎么回事?
- We're on our way to extract. - What happened?
没事了 你脸上中枪 伙计
You're good to go. You took one to the face, man.
你这个打不死的家伙
You're a hard motherfucker.
- 我们救到她了吗? - 是的
- Did we get her? - Yes.
- 哦 天啊 - 我们在撤退路上
- Oh, my God. - We're on our way to extract.
艾杰 冲啊 冲啊
Ajay, splash it. Splash it.
到河边了 到河边了！
Water! Water! Water!
冲河里了！冲河里了！
Going in! Going in!
我抬着她！我抬着她！
I got her! I got her!
车要沉了
It's fucking going under.
出去！他妈的快出去！
Out! Get the fuck out!
我们没白来
It wasn't for nothing.
乌克兰
干什么的?
门德尔松的曲子?
不是 勃拉姆斯的
克里莫夫在哪里?
你是谢布尔吧?
就像我在电话里跟克里斯多说的 我这儿有你想要的东西
很轻吧?
能穿在燕尾服里
衣服内部装着许多小陶瓷球
多达500个
衣服里织着新型凝胶炸药
这是毁灭性的武器
就是它
我知道它看起来不起眼
这是设计用于开放式环境的
相信我 世上没有比这威力更大的
单人操纵武器了
你看
一切都考虑到了
你可以穿着它自由进出白宫
我能看看演示吗?
你有空去西伯利亚吗?
这个玩意爆炸的时候
周围所有人都得死绝
想想有500颗子弹飞向四周
然后全部爆开来
你带着它去球场
或者是赌场 或者是购物商场
就会引起美国媒体的极大恐慌
接着你就会看到经济崩溃...
伙计 看看你
你还是老样子
- 需要我为您拿走外衣吗? - 不用 谢谢
知道吗 时不时地
You know, from time to time,
我会去看我的老朋友们
I get to see my old friends from my old life.
但总是 总是让人失望
And it's always, always disappointing.
有些人成了混蛋 另一些则很无趣
Some become assholes, other boring,
真不敢相信我以前跟他们交情那么好
and I can't believe I tried to get them in bed all those years ago.
嘿
Hey.
真高兴你没让我失望 尤里
It is nice not to be disappointed, Yuri.
- 这不是我的名字 - 我知道
- That's not my name. - I know.
默罕默德·阿布·谢布尔 谢布尔之子
Mohammed Abu Shabal, the son of Shabal
拜托 你父亲叫尤基尼
Come on. Your father's name is Yevgeny.
事情会变的
Things change.
是啊 是变了
Yeah, things have changed.
所以相当长时间内这应该是我最后一次见你了
That's why this is the last time we might have to see each other for quite some time.
因为我得找个地方躲起来
For I might have to find a hole to hide in.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我被中情局盯上了 我不想冒险
I'm being watched by the CIA, and I'm not taking any chances.
只要一有机会 我就举家南下
As soon as the opportunity presents itself, I'm taking my family south.
我既无能力又无动力和美国人作对
I neither have the energy or the will to fight the Americans.
我们的生意怎么办 米哈伊尔?
What about our deal, Mikhail?
我的人受训将近一年了
My men have been training for almost a year now.
- 我往里面砸了很多钱 - 合作仍然有效 尤里
- I have devoted much of my resources... - The deal stands, Yuri.
我提早“退休”不等于
Just because I've taken early retirement does not mean
我不管生意了
I'm not holding up my end of the bargain.
要做的事情还有很多
There is so much to be done.
都会继续的 只不过我不参与
And it will be, just without me.
你可以利用我信任的人
You'll have to use my trusted associates.
这根本不够
That's not so good for me.
- 嘿... - 嘿！闭嘴！
- Hey... - Hey! Shut up!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
别再满嘴胡言了！
Stop your fucking bullshit!
这不够 根本没用 你不能说变就变
It's not good. Doesn't work. You can't change it like that.
- 什么都没变啊 什么都没！ - 你刚跟我说一切都变了
- Nothing changes. Nothing. - You just told me everything's changed.
这又是怎么回事?这又是怎么回事?
What... What is that? What is that?
你知道我怎样才走到这一步?
Do you know what I do to get here?!
又牺牲了多少同胞?！
Do you know the men who I've had to sacrifice to get here?!
你懂不懂啊?！
Do you have any idea?!
根本就不懂 混蛋！你住在象牙塔里 什么都不管
No, you shit! You live up here in this ivory tower!
你根本...根本不在乎！
You have no... You don't care!
美国黄蜂级两栖攻击舰第6艘“好人理查德”号 中美洲海岸
上士 麦奇伤势怎样?
Hey, Chief, what's the status on Mikey?
眼睛保不住了 不过他能挺过去
He's definitely gonna lose the eye, but he's... he's hanging tough.
嘿 我得跟传达下表彰
Hey, I'm gonna get right into this.
你们沉重痛击了敌人 救回了莫拉里斯
Great job smoke-checking those assholes and getting Morales back.
对麦奇来说有点不划算 不过还是得说大家干得好
It's a bum deal for Mikey, but I gotta tell you what, that was solid work.
上士 你得把这些传达给兄弟们
So, Chief, you make sure you get that down to the boys right away.
- 听见了么? - 明白
- You hear me? - Check.
好的 现在我们谈谈莫拉里斯 她很坚强
All right. Now, Morales, Morales was one tough chick,
但是她让事情变化的很快
but she should've gotten the stuff up the chain a lot faster
因为事情比我们想象的要复杂的多
because this thing is way bigger than we thought it was.
怎么会?我以为这只是普通的美国人质营救行动
How is that? I thought this was a cut-and-dry AMCIT recovery.
是的 但是你们在那个地方找到的手机改变了一切
Yeah, it was until we got into that phone that you guys picked up in that shithole.
这让我觉得事情很不对劲
It turned me on to something that just does not look right at all.
- 哪不对了? - 克里斯多和谢布尔比我们想象要亲密的多
- And what's not right about it? - Christo and Shabal are a lot closer
谢布尔是个不安定因素
than I thought they were, and Shabal is a wild card, man.
他是个死板的圣战分子  对金钱和毒品一点儿也不在乎
He is an old-school jihadi that couldn't give a rat's ass about money or drugs.
是啊 那他的老朋友克里斯多 那个毒贩子呢?
Yeah, and his childhood friend, Christo, the dope dealer?
伙计 他是在搞走私 不是搞贩毒
He is not a dealer, man. He's a smuggler.
- 你一定在开玩笑 - 这就是我现在想的
- You have got to be kidding me. - That is exactly what I'm thinking.
谢布尔想杀美国人
Shabal wants to kill Americans.
克里斯多知道怎么把那些混蛋们带进美国
Christo knows how to get fuckers inside America.
这可是个大麻烦
This could be big trouble in little China, fellas.
他们要袭击美国本土
They're gonna hit us at home.
我刚跟特种部队和指挥官商量过
I just got done talking to the boss and the Spec Ops Task Force,
这是下一步的计划
and this is what's gonna go down.
让艾杰和雷准备两小时后登上潜艇
I need Ajay and Ray standing by to launch for an SR in two hours.
他们得乘“船”去非洲
They're gonna get some frequent flyer miles on the way to Africa.
为什么是非洲?
Why Africa?
根据你们得到的那个手机 我们跟踪到了非洲的一个机场
We pinned an airfield there with that phone that you got,
而且我认为谢布尔可能在那里向西边转移军火
and I think that Shabal is gonna be there doing a weapons transfer on his way west.
你说的西边指的是什么?墨西哥西部?
When you say "west," what are we talking about, Mexico west?
嗯 墨西哥西部 这是最坏的情况
Yeah, Mexico west. That's worst-case scenario.
你们两个和小队的其他成员在这儿待命
You two and the rest of the platoon are gonna stay here on standby.
如果有什么意外在美国附近发生
You'll be the primary assault force in case
你们将会是主要的突击力量
something goes down anywhere near America.
- 明白 - 明白
- Check. - Check.
他们现身时你会来随时帮忙吗?
You gonna be around for any questions as they come up?
不行 伙计 克里斯多给我留下了个烂摊子 然后消失了
No, man. Christo... he pulled a Roman Polanski on my ass and disappeared.
我得和海豹第四分队联系
So I'm gonna link up with SEAL Team Four,
我们去南太平洋把他抓回来
and we're gonna go hunt his ass down in the South Pacific.
所以我恐怕抽不开身
So it's straight up Mai Tais and palm trees for me, baby.
是啊 兄弟 把他抓回来
Yeah, brother. Go get him.
- 你保重 - 放轻松点
- You be cool. - Take it easy.
祝你做爸爸有好运 上尉
Good luck with that baby, Lieutenant.
- 每个人都知道么? - 只有重要人物知道
- Does everybody know? - Only the important people.
对谁来说是重要人物?你?
The important people to who? You?
我想是的
I guess so.
- 我去通知兄弟们 - 等等
- I'm gonna go brief the boys. - Hey, hold on one second.
嘿 哥们 我以前从来没写过这些东西
Hey, brother, I've never written one of these before.
我保证我会保护你的
Hey, I'm tracking with you, sir. I am.
不过 老实说
But, to be honest with you,
我曾打算报告头儿让你回家
I was thinking of calling the command and trying to get you home.
但现在事情变得糟糕了 我想我们需要你
But now that work's picked up so much, I feel like we really need you here.
你还记得我们上次在安巴尔的行动么?
You remember our last cruise to AI Anbar?
- 嗯 - 当你在执行那个转折性的任务时
- Yeah. - When you had that final
你说 我不必在到场?
turnover op, and you said I didn't need to be there?
我当时躺在床上 一心想要回家
I was laying in bed and I realized the only thing I needed to do now was go home.
但是如果你们的行动失败了
But if something went south on your op,
我会后悔我没有和你们在一起
I would always regret not being there with you.
我很感谢你一直这么照顾我 戴夫
I appreciate you taking care of me big-time, Dave,
但是我要跟队友在一起
but I'm working some things with the brass.
可以的话 等事情暂缓 我会休息两周
If I can, and things slow down, I'm gonna get two weeks off.
我真心希望一切顺利
Well, I hope it works out either way. I really do.
但如果失败 我会拿着这张纸
But, if it doesn't, I'm gonna take this piece of paper,
把它做成一架漂亮的纸飞机
and I'm gonna make it into a nice paper airplane.
走吧
Beat it.
非洲海岸
出发！出发！
We're good, we're good!
值更官 将潜艇下潜到160英尺
Chief of the Watch, submerge the ship to one-six-zero feet.
下潜 下潜
Dive. Dive.
潜望镜已收起 舱门密封良好
Scope down. All doors are green.
- 伙计们 - 长官
- Oh, good. Hey, guys. - Sir.
- 谢谢你们这么快就赶过来 - 理所应当
- Thank you for getting here so fast. - Sure.
- 请坐吧 - 谢谢
- Grab a seat, please. - Thank you.
“斗牛犬”会在你们上空
You'll have Bulldog overhead.
索马里 “斗牛犬”预警机
并带出情报 有问题么?
and bounce it back to us. Do you have any questions?
长官 我有问题 我们制定好了会合地点和时间
Sir, I have a question. We have the rally point and time.
可是如果他们没按计划出现呢?
What if the meeting doesn't take place as scheduled?
你想让我们盯着目标多长时间呢?
How long do you want us to stay on target?
这个已经考虑了 所以我计划让你们多呆一会
Now, this one counts, so I'd plan on being out there for a while.
- 明白 - 都明白了?
- Check. - Are we good?
- 我想是的 长官 - 是的 长官
- Think so, sir. - Yes, sir.
雷和艾杰已经装备整齐 互相检查
Ray and Ajay are rigged up and ready to check each other out.
闸门准备就绪
Garage door clear.
索马里
- 你看见了么? - 是的
- You got a visual? - Yeah.
看见了三辆卡车
Got three trucks moving in.
一辆油车 两辆吉普 后面坐着非洲民兵
A fuel truck, two jeeps, some skinnies in the back.
有辆车装着一把12.7毫米口径重机枪
One of them has a .50-cal.
你听见了么?
You hear that
- 嗯 我想那是我们的目标 - 是的 我们发现目标了
- Yeah, I think that's our plane. - Yeah, we got some inbound.
他们是时候现身了 天啊 给我相机
'Bout time these guys showed up. Jesus. Let me get my camera.
嘿 雷 两架飞机在机场尽头降落
Hey, Ray, we got two birds down at the end of the field,
在我们东南方向 没有尾翼编号
southeast our pos, no tail IDs.
- 记下没? - 记了 没有尾翼编号
- You got that? - Check, no tail IDs.
雷 我记得我们是在非洲吧
Ray, last time I checked, we were in Africa, right?
是啊 怎么了?
Yeah. Why, what's up?
兄弟 看上去那儿有16个菲律宾人
Dude, there's, like, 16 Filipinos down there,
都在向麦加祈祷呢
all praying to Mecca right now.
- 菲律宾人? - 是的 肯定不是非洲民兵
- Filipinos? - Filipinos. Definitely not skinnies.
我接受他们的祈祷了 顺便接受俄国人的祈祷
I'm picking up the praying. I'm also picking up some Russian.
你们两个人过来
小心照看这些箱子 听到了么?
要是掉了一个 我们都得死
你要换乘不同的飞机
然后穿越两条不同的边境线
为谨慎起见
一旦到达岛上 你的人会有时间进行准备
我的朋友会去接你 帮你搞定剩下的“路途”
斗牛犬 斗牛犬 我是红酒 无线电测试 请回
Bulldog, Bulldog, Redrum, radio check, over.
- 收到测试 - 明白 收到测试
- Good check, copy. - Roger, good check.
注意 我们侦察到两架不明飞机
Be advised, we got two sterile aircraft
向东起飞 方位是
departing to the east from following location:
10 P L S
Ten, Papa, Lima, Sierra.
侦测到目标后请回复 完毕
Please advise when tally target, over.
明白 两架飞机 方位 10 P
Roger Copy, two aircraft, location Ten, Papa...
嘿 上士 你不会相信的
Hey, Chief, you are not gonna believe this.
雷和艾杰标记的一架飞机
One of the planes Ray and Ajay tagged
刚刚降落在了墨西哥海岸的塞德罗斯岛
just landed on Cedros Island off the coast of Mexico.
机上坐着谢布尔和数量不明的圣战分子
It has Shabal on it with an unknown number of jihadis.
你在开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding me?
不 看起来我们可以去袭击目标了
No, looks like we're gonna get to hit that target.
好吧 军士和河流部队特战艇出发了
Well, Senior and the SWCC boats are punching out.
他们应该能弄到更多情报的 等着看吧
They should pull a little more intel for us, so we'll see.
好的
All right.
南太平洋
我不知道我们得待多久 等一下 宝贝
I don't know how long we're staying. Hold on, baby.
- 注意安全 - 你知道我会的
- Be safe. - You know I will.
- 我要出发了 宝贝 - 我爱你
- I gotta go, honey, - I love you.
我也爱你
I love you.
乔安娜 我不想你跟那些男孩玩
你在听我说么?
好吗?好的 以后再和你聊
A队B队 距离目标200米
Bravo Alpha, we're 200 meters out.
B队 侦察到右舷有一名目标
Bravo, you have a Tango on your starboard side.
右舷有一名目标
MAN 2 Tango on the starboard side.
C队W队 侦察到敌方目标
Whiskey Charlie, we have a visual on Tango.
B队 12点钟方向有埋伏
Bravo, you have a Viper at twelve o'clock.
趴下！趴下！
Get down! Get down!
安全！舰桥安全
Clear! Bridge secure.
军士 可安全上船
Senior, you're clean
下午好 你好么?
你还好么?你还说塞尔维亚-克罗地亚语么?
我会俄语
你是俄罗斯人?
是的
我不说俄语
- 英语可以么?开始吧 - 没问题
- English OK? Let's do that. - English is fine.
能给他松绑么?
Can you cut him loose, please?
如果松了绑 你不会做傻事的 对吧?
If you get cut loose, you're not gonna do anything crazy, are you?
所谓“疯子伊凡”
A Crazy Ivan? Soto speak.
那么你是俄国人吧 是吗?
So you're Russian, yeah?
- 是的 - 你没事吧?
- Yes, I am. - You all right?
- 是的 没事 谢谢 - 不客气
- Yes, I'm good. Thank you. - You're welcome.
抱歉 我还不知道你的名字
I'm sorry. I don't know your name.
- 我是奥托 - 奥托
- I'm Otto. - Otto.
- 对 你呢? - 很高兴见到你
- Yes. And you are? - Nice to meet you.
克里斯多
Christo.
- 克里斯科? - 克里斯多
- Crisco? - Christo.
特拉斯科维奇?
Troskawicz?
还要跟你混多久才能
So how long am I gonna need to keep busting your balls
得到一块这种补丁?
about getting one of those patches?
啊 我想不会再有了
Ah, yeah, I think it was, like, a one-time deal, man.
911之后 我叔叔给我们队送了一堆
After 9/11, my uncle sent a bunch out for the platoon,
不过这次行动后 我会把它给你
but, uh, after this go-round, I'll give it to you.
不 不 我不会拿你的家族饰品
No, no, I'm not gonna take your family crest.
好吧 其实我也不想给你
All right, good. I didn't want to give it to you anyway.
除此之外 我很确定我看见
Besides, man, I'm pretty sure I saw you
几天前你把什么东西放到了你的口袋里
putting something in your cargo pocket the other day.
- 那是什么? - 我知道我见过你那个
- What's that? - I know I've seen you carrying
口袋里装了什么东西
something in that pocket right there.
是什么?
What is it?
这是我祖父的旗子
That's my grandfather's flag.
- 真棒 - 我爸爸把他给了我
- Nice. - My pop gave it to me,
哪天我会把它给我的孩子
and now I'm gonna give it to my boy someday.
棒极了 我喜欢
All right. I like that.
你在一艘很漂亮的船上
You're sitting on a wonderful boat.
- 它很豪华 - 没错 谢谢
- It's fabulous. - Thank you. Yes.
- 我觉得它叫“星际飞船” - “星际飞船”
- I believe it's called Starship. - "Starship,"
我喜欢你说“星际飞船”的方式
I love the way you say Starship.
听上去像俄语 像一个《星际迷航》里的人
It's like Russian. That guy, uh... Star Trek.
叫什么来着 斯科蒂?哦 不 对不起 斯科特
What's his name, Scotty? Oh, no, he was, sorry, Scott.
- 我不知道 - 你从没看过《星际迷航》?
- I wouldn't Know. - Yes. You've never seen Star Trek?
- 没 - 你“疯”了
- No. - Oh, that's insane.
- 问题是这样的 伙计 - 嗯?
- So here's the problem, pal. - Mm-hm?
你身价很高
You're worth a lot of money.
- 或者说你曾经身价很高 - 我相信我现在也是
- Or you were worth a lot of money. - I believe I still am.
- 是么? - 没错
- You do? - Yes.
好吧 让我告诉你这个世界是怎么运转的吧 克里斯科
All right. Let me tell you how the world works there, Crisco.
- 是克里斯多 - 什么?
- It's Christo. - Sorry?
- 克里斯多 - 哦 当然了 抱歉
- Christo. - Oh, of course. Sorry.
没事
It's OK.
让我来告诉你这世界是怎么运转的
Let me tell you how the world really works.
- 请吧 - 这不再是你的船了
- Please. - This is no longer your boat.
从我穿过那扇门之后 你再也不是原来的你了
Since I walked through that door, you're not the same guy you used to be.
就是这样的 我也没法阻止
You're just not. There's nothing I can do to stop that,
我帮不了你 除非你让我帮你
nothing I can do to help you right now, unless you let me help you.
我们需要共渡难关 兄弟 你和我
We need to do this together, pal. You and me.
跟伊斯兰圣战分子共事感觉如何?
So how is it that you're working with these jihadi folks, then?
你是犹太人 对么?
You're Jewish, right?
谢布尔是什么?
Shabal is what?
- 你有没有跟你一起长大的朋友? - 什么?
- You got a friend, like, you grew up with? - Sorry?
你有跟你一起长大的朋友吗?
Have you ever had a friend that you grew up with?
- 是的 - 有共同的兴趣 都踢足球
- Yes. - Had, like, played interests, played soccer,
或是...你们玩的什么 可能是棒球 对吧?
or... What would you play? Baseball, probably, right?
- 可能吧 - 是的
- Probably. Yeah. - Yeah.
后来大家各奔前程
And then you went on your separate ways,
数年后再遇见时
and then some years later, you meet up.
你完全认不出他来了
And you totally didn't recognize the person.
这就是我和谢布尔的故事
And that's what happened with Shabal.
我们有共同的爱好
We share a common interest.
因为宗教信仰 他突然有了不可思议的想法
So he came up with this incredible idea because of his beliefs.
我不必跟他有一样的信仰 但他是个聪明人
I don't necessarily share his beliefs, but he's a smart guy.
知道吗 就好像...
You know, it's almost like...
就好像...
...you know, it's almost like...
这就是我
...like this is me.
- 这就是谢布尔 - 是吗?
- And that's Shabal. - Is it?
- 中间是美国人 - 是么?
- And America is in-between. - Is it?
没错
Yeah.
很酷的理论吧?
Cool concept, no?
- 在这里? - 是的
- Right here? - Yes.
你认为这是游戏?
You think this is some kind of game?
- 是吗?你觉得这很好笑么? - 不 不
- Do you? Do you find this amusing? - No. No.
- 我没觉得 - 你知道自己在这做什么吗?
- I'm not finding... - Do you realize what you're doing here?
基地呼叫黑胡小队
Blackbeard Actual, this is Blackbeard Main.
目标B已清除
Post nation counterpart. Secured target Bravo.
通告全队 可以安全前往目标A
Report to Tri-Hull. You're clear to move on target Alpha.
收到基地 朝目标行进中
MAN 2 Roger, Main. Clear to target.
我只会向我的家人坦白
The only people I answer to is my family.
向我的妻子和我的孩子
To my wife and to my child.
除此之外 别无他人
And nobody else.
- 你赶时间么? - 不想再听你说废话了
- Running late somewhere? - Shit filter's full.
- 真的? - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
问题是这样的 兄弟
So here's the problem, pal.
你爱你的家人 对吧?
You do love your family, don't you?
- 是的 - 那你的女儿呢?
- Yes, I do. - And what about your daughter?
我的女儿?
What about my daughter?
你还想再看到她么?
Are you looking forward to seeing her again?
无时无刻都想见
Every minute of my life.
我让你看这个是想让你好好考虑下
I wanted you to see that so that you'd think about some things very seriously,
因为你会被关进某个“笼子”
because you're gonna be sitting in a box somewhere.
你会得到妥善和人道的待遇
You'll be treated properly and humanely.
这个女孩将会长大 结婚
That girl is gonna grow up, and she's gonna get married,
你老婆也会再嫁他人
and your wife is gonna find someone else,
你会错过一切的
and you're gonna miss everything.
如果我做了什么让家人置身危险的事
If I had done something that would endanger my family,
我会跟你现在有同样的想法
I would feel just like you do right now.
你能保证不碰我家人吗?
You promise not to touch my family?
我绝不会碰你家人
I would never touch your family.
我不会
I would not.
你对
Are you familiar with...
陶瓷球熟悉么?
...ceramic ball bearings?
不
No.
想象一下 16件
Just imagine 16 suicide vests
装有陶瓷球的自爆背心
filled with those ceramic ball bearings,
通过金属探测仪和美国所有检查站
slipping by every metal detector and every checkpoint in your country.
现在能想象到经济崩溃了吗?
You think your economy is fucked now?
想象下媒体会怎么应对这事
Just think what the media is gonna do with this. Hm?
这会使911事件变得微不足道
It's gonna make 9/11 look like a fucking walk in the park.
就像在中央公园里散步一样
The grand Central Park.
你这是在告诉我
So you're telling me...
会有16个圣战分子穿着自爆背心
...there's 16 jihadis wearing suicide vests.
大摇大摆穿越边境
They're gonna walk right across the border.
那他们的目的地是哪里?
So where are they going?
圣地亚哥, 旧金山,休斯顿
San Diego, San Francisco, Houston...
随你选 到处都有
You pick a city, they'll be there.
- 这就是现在的事态么? - 我们说话时它就在发生着
- And this is happening now? - It's happening as we speak.
什么?
Sorry, what?
现在它就在发生着 就在我们说话的时候
It's happening as we speak.
你怎么才能阻止?
How can you stop this?
我不能
I can't.
赛德罗斯岛 墨西哥
黑胡 后援队已就位
Blackbeard Lead, containment element is set.
明白
Roger.
卡洛斯, 门口有人！ 救命！救命！
开火！开火！开火！
Gun! Gun! Gun!
安全！
Clear!
- 走 - 我们走！
- Go. - Coming out!
鼠帮 我是黑胡 我们在中心地带 即教堂南部与敌军交火
Rat Pack, this is Blackbeard. We're in contact, midtown, south of the church.
接敌！
Contact!
更换弹药！
Changing!
黑胡 你的方位是什么?
Blackbeard Lead, what's your pos?
掩护我, 你可自由射击
Overwatch. You're clear to engage.
开火！
Go in hot.
小心手雷！
Frag out!
怀明 我看到两个目标正开车向南逃窜
Weimy, I've got two squilters heading south in a pickup truck.
我看见了
I see 'em.
狠狠揍卡车里那两个家伙
Hit those two guys in the truck.
火箭弹！
Rocket!
小心手雷！
Frag out!
长官?长官?
Sir? Sir?
上尉?你没事吧?
LT? You all right?
妈的
Damn.
这玩意救了你一命 是吧?
You check that box, huh?
嗯
Yeah.
幸运的是那是颗哑弹 本来我应该受伤的
Good thing that was a dud. I might've gotten hurt.
- 是啊 - 哇哦
- Yeah. - Whoa.
天啊
Jesus.
这可不是伊拉克手工作坊那种劣质自爆背心
This is not some bush-league vest from an Iraqi hut.
它装着高速弹丸
This is some high-speed shit.
我们或许该把它放到别的地方 是吧?
Maybe we should put this somewhere else, huh?
桑尼, 把这放到别的地方 好吗?
Hey, Sonny, find somewhere to put this, would you?
目标安全! 设置警戒区！
Target secure. Set security.
一个去北面 3个去南面
One's to the north, three south.
这是你们的目标
嘿 上士 目标搞定了
Hey, Chief, target's buttoned up.
- 一切都安全了 - 谢谢 兄弟
- Everything's secure. - Thanks, man.
黑胡 任务并未完成 请待命
WOActual, mission not complete. Stand by for follow-on.
你只解决了一半的恐怖分子
You only got half that jihadist cell.
- 目标安全 长官 - 行动还没结束
- The target's secure, sir. - This fight isn't over yet.
听着 另一半的恐怖分子在7点时
Now, listen, the other half of that cell is gonna be crossing the border
会从墨西卡利利用地下通道穿过国界
using a tunnel network from Mexicali at 0700.
正和州政府协调中 不过直升机会先把你们送到城市外围
We're coordinating with State, but for now the birds will drop you off
接头人是指挥官佩卓斯
outside the city where your POC is a Commander Pedros.
路上我会给你更多的细节
I 'll give you more details en route.
- 黑胡 收到没? - 收到 基地
- Actual, how do you copy? - Roger, Main.
好的 甲板上有接送我们的直升机
OK, we've got a helo landing on the deck,
我们将跟墨西哥特种部队及其指挥官碰面
we're gonna meet a Mexican SOF commander and his team.
他们会帮我们渗透目标并参与突击
They're gonna help infil us to the target and join us on the assault.
- 你究竟在说什么? - 我们还没有完全消灭他们 上士
- What the hell are you talking about? - We haven't got all of 'em yet, Chief.
- 剩下的在哪儿? - 他们在墨西卡利边境上
- And where's the rest of 'em? - They're in Mexicali on the border.
好的 那剩下的人
All right. And the rest of the boys,
怎么回船上去?
how are they getting back to the ship?
好人理查号会继续待命
Bon Homme Richard stayed on station.
他们会派出一支陆战小队去帮助清理战场
They're gonna send in a Marine element to help exploit the target.
完事后剩下的人会跟他们一起走
When they're done, the boys will pull off with them.
好的.我在想让一小队和我去执行任务
OK. I'm thinking Squad One and myself roll out.
很好 二小队在这里驻守
Perfect. Squad Two stays here, buttons it up,
- 和陆战队一起撤退 - 没问题
- pulls out with the Marines. - OK.
在日出之前我们
We're moving north of here through town,
从这里向北穿过镇子
and crossing at sunrise.
另一组会在几天内到达德克萨斯
The other group will get into Texas the following day,
通过华瑞兹市
through Juarez.
明白吗?
Comprendes ?
嘿 长官,！到底谁下令派我们去墨西卡利的?
Hey, sir! Who the hell cleared us hot to go to Mexicali anyway?
是高层的命令
This one's going all the way up the flagpole.
国务院决定的
State Department's on it.
美墨边界
嘿 长官 2号频道
Hey, sir. Channel two.
嘿 如果任务还是没完没了
Hey, this tempo keeps up like this,
那杰姬得自己想法生孩子了
Jackie's gonna be squeezing that kid out on her own.
不过如果我们迅速完成任务
However, we hit this target quick enough,
你就能骑驴回家了
you jump on a burro and ride that shit home.
我可不需要一只驴子
Hey, I ain't gonna need no burro.
你拿到2周假期了?
Did you get your two weeks?
卫星电话不是白打的
All that time I was spending on the sat phone,
我不是求上面让我回家
it wasn't to convince them to let me go home,
而是求他们让你负责任务
it was to convince them to leave your ass in charge.
美墨边界
- 长官 - 上尉
- Sir. - Lieutenant.
看起来政府为了促成这事做了很大努力 是吧?
Seems our governments have been very busy to make this possible, huh?
我听说是最高层决定的
All the way to the top, from what I hear.
有些事情你必须明白
There is something that you have to understand.
我的上司很害怕事情演变成墨西哥版的“黑鹰坠落”
My superiors, they're very fearful of a Mexican Mogadishu.
他们的要求就是不能派黑鹰去
No Black Hawk Down is what they're saying,
所以我们要小心行事
so we do need to stay under the radar.
- 完全明白 长官 - 好的
- I understand completely, sir. - Good.
我很感谢你们来帮忙 但是我们时间不多
Your team's presence here is greatly appreciated, but we are out of time.
- 得马上行动 - 告诉我地点 我们就出发
- We need to move. - Tell me where, we go.
帮我整合这些信息
Help piece this together for me.
- 没问题 - 我们的情报显示
- OK. - Our intel says
他们会使用地下通道 在“制奶厂”下面
they're using a tunnel network that is under a milk factory.
这对你来说意味什么?
This mean anything to you?
我知道确切位置 离这里不远
I know exactly where that is. It's not far from here.
那就是我们的目的地
Then that's where we're going.
这或许是整个墨西卡利
Of all of the places in Mexicali
最糟糕的地方了
that you could have picked, this is probably the worst.
贩毒集团控制着这个地区的各个角落
The cartels control that area from all angles.
他们火力强大
They have us heavily outgunned.
单是接近目标就很艰难
Simply reaching your target is gonna be very difficult.
长官 有8个“外国公民”正要进入我们国家
Sir, we have eight foreign nationals heading to our country.
无需多说 他们肯定不喜欢美国人
Needless to say, they are no big fan of ours.
如果他们在那里 那就是我们的目的地
If they are at that factory, that's where we're going.
上尉 我会带你去任何你要去的地方
Lieutenant, I'll take you anywhere you need to go,
但是 让你的部下准备进行比想象中还激烈的战斗吧
but prepare your men for a bigger fight than what you had imagined.
你不仅仅是和8个人作战 更是和他们背后的贩毒集团作战
You're not fighting eight men. You're also fighting the cartel that's protecting them.
如果目标进入了地下通道
If your targets make it into those tunnels,
那他们会像幽灵一样消失
they'll disappear like ghosts.
你从这里进入通道
You enter the tunnels right here.
你需要步行七英里到达交叉口
You will walk seven miles to this fork.
我的人会告诉你该去哪个隧道
My men will tell you what tunnel to take.
当你到了那里 我的任务就完成了
Once you get to this point, my job is done.
到时候就靠自己了
You're on your own.
- 上尉 我们要进去了！ - 明白
- Lieutenant, we're going now! - Roger that.
上士, 不要停下 我们要冲进去
Chief, we're not stopping. We're rolling up on target, hard.
明白 长官 30秒准备
Roger that, sir. We're about 30 seconds out.
距南边入口一分钟
One mike out from the south entrance.
老大！在房顶上！
Jefe! On the roof!
我们得走了 快！
We gotta go. Now.
我们走
你待在这里
长官！留两个人在这！
Sir! Leave two men here!
准备好 他们来了！
怀明！
Weimy!
我要你把这些混蛋搞定！
I need you to lock this shit down!
小心手雷！
Frag out!
跟着我
On me.
你们去那边的门！
You guys got the gate!
卡尔！你去前门！
Call! You're going to the front door!
上!
Go!
卡尔！
Call!
更换弹药！
Changing!
炸弹！
Bomb!
我们干嘛停下?
该死的 长官
Damn it, sir.
我要怎么跟家里人解释啊?
How you gonna explain that one to my family?
退回去就不用解释这事了 是吧?
Get back there so I don't have to, huh?
安全！
Clear!
小心手雷！
Grenade!
上尉！
LT!
上士 我来帮他
Chief, I got him.
继续行动 我来掩护你
Keep going. I'll cover you.
快进隧道
上士
Chief.
上士！
Chief!
突击2队 我是突击1队
Assault Two, this is Assault One.
注意 地下通道已安全 所有目标已击毙
Be advised, tunnel is secure and all threats are neutralized.
上尉和上士倒下了
LT and Chief are down.
重复一遍, 上尉和上士倒下了
I say again, LT and Chief are down,
你父亲是个好男人
Your father was a good man.
幼年丧父会让你感到艰辛
Growing up without him is gonna be hard.
感到痛苦
It's gonna hurt.
感到孤独 感觉迷失了“海岸线”
You'll feel alone, out to sea, with no shore in sight.
你会纳闷“为什么是我?我什么是我的父亲?”
You'll wooden "Why me? Why him?"
但请记住 你血管里流淌着勇士的鲜血
Remember, you have warrior's blood in your veins.
造就你父亲的“准则”
The code that made your father who he was is the same code
也将同样使你变成他所尊敬的男子汉
that'll make you a man he would admire, respect.
把你的悲伤放进“盒子”里 锁起来
Put your pain in a box. Lock it down.
正如你父亲所钟爱的绘画里的人物
Like those people in the paintings your father liked,
我们也是由各要素“组成”的
we are men made up of boxes, chambers of loss and triumph,
损失、胜利、伤痛、希望和爱
of hurt and hope and love.
- 没有人比能够驾驭情绪和 - 准备！
- No one is stronger or more dangerous... - Ready!
- 面对过去的人更坚强 - 瞄准！
- ...Than a man who can harness emotions. - Aim!
或更强大
His past.
瞄准！
Aim!
望你能以此作为动力 作为激励
Use it as fuel, as ammunition,
作为书写生命华美篇章之墨
as ink to write the most important letter of your life.
我谨代表美国总统
On behalf of the President of the United States
和这满怀感激之情国家 授予你这面国旗
and a grateful nation, I present you this flag
以此纪念你的丈夫的英雄事迹
in recognition of your husband's heroic achievements.
对此 我表示最深刻的哀悼
You have my deepest condolences.
还有一面旗帜要交予你
One more flag to present.
我想你认识这个
This one I think you know.
每次行动 洛克都会带着它
On every deployment, Rorke carried this with him.
再一次表达我最深刻的哀悼
Again, my deepest condolences.
上尉！恩格尔！
Lieutenant Engel!
呼拉 上尉 恩格尔！
Hoo-yah, Lieutenant Engel!
你父亲临死前让我转达你一首图康萨的诗
Before he died, your father asked me to give you this poem by Tecumseh.
我告诉他我会把它写下来 折成纸飞机
I told him I 'd fold it into a paper airplane.
我想我也是这么做的
And, in a way, I guess that's what I'm doing,
以下是他想告诉你的：
sailing it from him to you.
永远不可让内心屈服于
Live your life that the fear of death
死亡的恐惧
Can never enter your heart
不可干涉别人的信仰
Trouble no one about his religion
尊重他人及其观点
Respect others and their views
同时也请他们尊重你
And demand they respect yours
热爱生命 诠释生命
Love your life, perfect your life
让你生命中的一切都变得美好
Beautify all things in your life
在有限的生命中坚持为民众服务
Seek to make your life long and of service to your people
当你生命走向终点时
When your time comes to die
别像其他人那样内心充满死亡恐惧
Be not like those whose hearts are filled with fear of death
他们在临死前会哭泣 会祈求上天
So that when their time comes they weep and pray
再给自己多一点时间去体验完全不同的人生
For a little more time to live their lives over again in a different way
你应吟着死亡之歌迎接终结
Sing your death song
要像个勇士...归家的勇士...
And die like a hero going home
（空军中尉托马斯·亨利·洛克 1919.3.20-1945.1.5）
（海军上尉洛克·詹姆士·恩格尔 1973.6.28-2010.9.29）
本片谨献给下列自911以来为国壮烈捐躯的海军特种作战勇士
级别从高到低排列： Lieutenant Commander=海军少校 Lieutenant=海军上尉
Master Chief Petty Officer=副总军士长 Senior Chief Petty Officer=高级军士
Chief Petty Officer=海军上士 Petty Officer=士官 数字代表等级
以及所有后继作战勇士们...
“少数拯救多数”
片名：勇者行动
勇士常在 希望长存
# AH I saw was smoke and fire #
# I didn't feel a thing #
# But suddenly I was rising higher #
# And I felt like I just made #
# The biggest mistake #
# When I thought about my unborn child #
# And when I thought about my wife #
# And the answer rang out clear #
# From somewhere up above #
# No greater gift has man #
# Than to la y down his life for love v
# And I wonder #
# Would I give my life? #
# Could I make that sacrifice? #
# If it came down to it Couldl take the bullet? #
# I would Yes, I would #
# For you #
# Mm-hm #
# Maybe you don't understand #
# I don't understand it all myself #
# But there's a brother on my left and another on my right #
# And in his pocket just like mine #
# He's got a photograph #
# And they're waiting for him back home #
# And it's weighing on my mind #
# I'm not trying to be a hero #
# I don't wanna die #
# But right now in this moment #
# You don't think twice #
# I wonder Would I give my life? #
# Could I make that sacrifice? #
# If it came down to it Couldl take the bullet? v
# I would Yes, I would #
# You don't think about right #
# You don't think about wrong #
# You just do what you gotta do #
# To defend your own #
# And I'd do the same #
# For you Yes, I would #
# Yes, I would #
# I would give my life #
# I would make that sacrifice #
# 'Cause if it came down to it #
# Couldl take a bullet? I would #
# Yes, I would #
# I'd do it for you #
# Yeah #
# Oh #
# Take the bullet #
# Yeah #
# Yes, I would #